SAI GUTTA

sairao77@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/saigutta https://sairao77.github.io

Microsoft Certified Office 365 Administrator with over 9+ years of experience in Windows Server Management, SharePoint Administration, End-User support, configuring and maintaining cloud computing solutions like Office 365, and Azure. Looking to leverage my knowledge and experience as a Cloud Solutions Architect.

EXPERIENCE

OCT 2020 - PRESENT

SENIOR ENGINEER, OFFICE 365, 2SEVENTY BIO (SPIN OFF FROM BLUEBIRD BIO)

- Manage all the workloads as an administrator and developer in Microsoft 365 tenant, a few examples below.
 - SharePoint
 - Manage company wide intranet using in built features in SharePoint and third party tools like LiveTiles
 - Setup policies for secure external data sharing with vendors and business partners, and configure org-wide access control for secure access to data for internal users.
 - Teams
 - Setup and maintenance of Teams meeting, live event, messaging, and voice policies
 - Setup direct routing for Teams voice along with dynamic emergency call routing
 - Project lead to implement governance on Modern Workplace apps e.g., automatic teams renewal through group expiration policy, retention policies on teams chats and posts for better information management within Teams
 - Exchange Online
 - Configuration and maintenance of mailflow settings to avoid unexpected mail loss and ensure security from end to end through SPF, DMARC, and DKIM
 - Utilizing open source libraries like PnP PowerShell to
 - Generate report on permissions used within SharePoint sites, including unique item/document level permissions, utilized to secure sites deemed as confidential and important
 - Automate SharePoint storage space management by authoring and executing scripts that perform regular clean up of large sites by trimming file versions to ensure efficient and cost effective space management
 - o Created PowerShell Scripts using MS Graph SDK, Azure AD, Exchange Online, and SharePoint Online modules to
 - Extract exchange resource usage (conference rooms and equipment) to provide usage-insights to the Facilities team that were used to consolidate building floor usage and reduce operation costs
 - Automate clean-up of stale users in Microsoft Entra on a regular intervals that helped with saving on licensing costs by 40%
 - Develop applications in Power Apps and improve business processes using Power Automate, a few examples below
 - Everyday security tours by facilities, where an RFID is scanned using Power Apps, and data is captured on to SharePoint
 - Automatic posting of announcements in Teams through Graph uri, when an email arrives in a user's inbox using Power Automate
 - Using Power Automate to send an email with embedded Adaptive Card Payload for Survey so that end users can answer directly from their Outlook
 - Other workloads that I support are PowerBI, Project (web and legacy version), Viva Connections, Viva Insights, Loop,
 Power Platform, Whiteboard, Visio, etc
- Develop custom solutions and deploy them in SharePoint using SharePoint Framework (SPFx)
 - Organizational and public holiday for user's display, accessible on SharePoint and Teams using Adaptive Card Extension
 - Travel Notice Reporting for end users using Adaptive Card Extension
 - An app on Teams Viva for end users to fill out while they are travelling so that our infosec team is notified and will automatically resolve any notifications that pop up in SOC about users logging in from unusual work locations.

Alert notifications on all communication SharePoint pages using Application Customizer Extensions
 Display notifications of various types to the whole organization on all SharePoint sites (can be restricted to certain site types) for example, regular covid related organization notifications for end users can be announced on SharePoint pages

Box

- Administer Box setup, support everyday requests from end users, manage regular updates to the application, and perform periodic reviews to make sure it is GxP compliant as per life sciences industry standards
- Design and implement governance rules like retention policies, and security policies for threat detection and data loss prevention
- Streamline everyday work for end users by helping them with automation workflows for their process, and setting up folder templates for easy startup of repeated processes

Microsoft Azure

- Manage resources and settings on Azure AD to support functioning of Microsoft 365 and enterprise custom applications
- O Design and configure Azure AD Connect and Cloud Sync for synchronization of identities from AD to cloud
- O Support application developers to setup, manage, and maintain Infrastructure on Azure
- Other tools that I support everyday include

RubrikDocuSignSmartSheet

MAY 2013 - OCT 2020

PROGRAMMER ANALYST II, MMS HOLDINGS INC.

Below are the applications that I administered, configured, and maintained, and tasks executed in this role.

•	Global	Administ	ration -	Office	365

- SharePoint Online Administration Azure Active Directory Teams & Skype For Business Administration
- Exchange Online Administration
 Azure AD Connect
 Security and Compliance
- Azure Tenant Administration
 - Windows Virtual Desktop
 Azure App Service
 Compute (Virtual Machine)
 - Storage Account
 Virtual Network
 Cost Management
- Migration, Upgrade, and Hybrid Infrastructure Setup
 - Data migration of SharePoint on-premises (2003, 2007,2010, 2013)
 Upgrade SharePoint 2010 to 2013 to SharePoint Online
 - © Exchange hybrid setup and migration of mailbox to Exchange Online
 - Installation of cumulative updates for EX 2013

Others

- Active Directory, DHCP & DNS
 Group Policy Object
 Zendesk Administration
 Barracuda Backup & Backup Exec
 Administration and Maintenance
- VMware Horizon Cloud
 TrendMicro
 GoDaddy & Network Solutions account
- VMware vSphere Windows Desktop 7, 8, 8.1, 10 Windows Server Management
- Network Storage Management
 Identity Life Cycle Management
 HTML and JavaScript

EDUCATION

MAY 2013

M.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE

EASTERN MICHIGAN UNIVERSITY, MI, U.S.A.

GPA: 3.85

MAY 2011

B. TECH INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

ANNA UNIVERSITY, TN, INDIA. **GRADE:** FIRST CLASS WITH DISTINCTION

CERTIFICATION

- Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator Associate
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate Office 365
- Microsoft 365 Certified: Teams Administrator Associate
- Microsoft Certified: Information Protection Administrator Associate







